Okay, stand by, everyone.
全體準備
Five, four, three, two...
五，四，三，二…
At 52 minutes past the hour on this Thursday morning, welcome back.
本週四早晨已過去52分鐘，歡迎回來
Joining me now is author Bill Bryson.
本次來參加節目的是作家比爾·布萊森
So, travel writing.
那麼，旅行寫作
I'm sorry, is that a question?
不好意思，這是個問題嗎？
Noel Coward once said, "Why do the wrong people travel,"
諾埃爾·科沃德曾說「為何失敗者旅行」
"and the right people stay at home?"
「而成功者卻待在家裏？」
Now, tell us about this Collector's Edition Box Set.
咱們來談談這個珍藏版合輯吧
"An elegant reissue of old favorites."
"舊時代收藏的再次發行"
Riveting stuff.
有趣的玩意兒
Now, in your books, you've written about Europe, Australia, the British Isles.
在你的書中，你談到了歐洲，談到了澳大利亞，還談到了大不列顛
You actually lived there briefly.
你都在那些地方逗留過？
Briefly. 10 years.
不長，就十年
Mmm, but never America.
但從沒提到美國
You've never written about your home country.
你從未寫到自己的祖國
- No, that's not exactly right... - Why? Why nothing more personal?
- 不，那可未必… - 為什麼？為什麼不寫點個人的東西？
I see. So you've moved back, or is that just temporary?
好吧，那麼你是搬回去了呢，還是暫時逗留？
No. Yes. My family, we moved back. To New Hampshire.
不，是的，我家人… 我們都搬回去了，搬到了新罕布什爾州
Twenty years ago. And... And we're still here.
20年前就搬了，而且…而且我們現在還在那
"Still"? Interesting choice of words.
「還在」？這個說法很有意思
Uh, what else are you working on? Are you writing something new?
你還在忙些別的什麼嗎？有沒有寫什麼新書？
No.
沒有
Not thinking of retiring on us, are you?
你該不會是想退休了吧？
No, writers don't retire.
不，作家沒有退休一說
We either drink ourselves to death or blow our brains out.
我們要麼把自己灌到不省人事，要麼就絞盡腦汁
And which will it be for you?
你會是哪一種？
After this interview, maybe both.
訪談結束後，可能兩者都是
- Bill Bryson, pleasure to have you with us. - Ah. Thank you.
- 比爾·布萊森，很高興你能參加節目 - 謝謝
- Oh. Hello, stranger. - Hello, yourself.
- 你好啊，陌生人 - 你也好
How'd it go?
訪談怎麼樣？
- You saw? - Mmm-hmm.
- 你看到了？ - 恩啊
- That good, huh? - Hey, Gramps.
- 還不錯，是吧？ - 嗨，外公
- Hi. - I saw, too.
- 你好 - 我也看了
- Oh, yeah? How'd I look? - Do you want my honest answer?
- 是嗎？我表現怎麼樣？ - 你想要我說實話嗎？
Never mind.
算了吧
- Gramps, I made it to level six. - Level six? Way to go.
- 外公，我打到第六關了 - 第六關？幹得漂亮
Did you get my message about Earl McGregor?
你聽說厄爾·麥格雷戈的事了嗎？
Services are on Saturday morning.
葬禮在週六早上
Can't we just send flowers?
咱們就不能只送花嗎？
We could.
可以啊
You two, hands washed, dinner's nearly ready. Let's go.
你們倆，去洗手，晚飯馬上就好，快去
Makes you think about slowing down, doesn't it?
會讓你反思人生該慢一點，不是嗎？
I'm so, so sorry. My condolences.
我非常非常遺憾，節哀順變
Deborah, we're so sorry.
黛博拉，我們深表遺憾
Thank you so much for being here. It really means a lot to me.
非常感謝你們能來，這對我來說很重要
It's our pleasure.
我們很樂意
Uh, I mean, not our... Pardon me.
我是說，我們不是…請原諒我
Uh, I mean, it's, uh, not a pleasant time,
我的意思是，現在，不是什麼歡樂的時刻
- and it's not a time... - No, we're just very sorry.
- 也不是該… - 沒錯，我們只是非常遺憾
- We're very sorry.
- 我們非常遺憾 - 非常遺憾
- I'll get my jacket. - We just got here.
- 我去拿我的外套 - 我們才剛到這
What? We've already paid our respects. I mean, what else are we supposed to do?
怎麼？我們已經表達了敬意，還能做什麼？
Talk to people. It's good for you.
和人們說說話，這對你有好處
I don't like talking to people.
我不喜歡和人講話
Go on.
快去
How are you? How good to see you.
你好嗎？很高心見到你
I'm gonna go for a walk.
我去散散步
Okay.
行啊
What on earth?
搞什麼鬼
- You want to hike it? - Yes.
- 你想徒步去？ - 沒錯
Two thousand miles.
2000英里
2118, actually.
準確說是2118英里
No. You can't.
不，不行
Why not?
為什麼？
Seriously, Bill. Even for you this is ridiculous.
說真的，比爾，即便對你來講這都很荒唐
Why? Because you think I'm too old?
為什麼？就因為你覺得我太老了？
No, it's not because I think you're too old, it's because you are too old.
不，不是我覺得你老，而是你真的老了
Oh, God, is this because of the funeral?
哦，天吶，是因為那場葬禮嗎？
- No. - What then?
- 不是 - 那是什麼？
Listen, I can't explain it.
我沒法解釋清楚
Have a go.
你試一試啊
It's just something I feel I have to do.
我只是跟著感覺走
I want to explore nature. I want to get back to my roots.
我想去探索自然，我想去尋根
- Roots? - Yeah. You know, push myself.
- 尋根？ - 對，逼自己一把
I mean, really, really hike.
我指的是真真正正的徒步旅行
Hike? You haven't hiked in 30 years.
徒步旅行？你都三十年沒徒步過了
- Exactly. - Can't you just do this in the Volvo?
- 完全正確 - 你就不能開車去嗎？
Catherine.
凱瑟琳
What if I say you can't go?
要是我不讓你去呢？
Well, if you felt that way then we would discuss it.
如果那樣的話，咱們就好好談談唄
You mean I'll yammer on and you'll nod away,
你是說我喋喋不休然後你點頭稱是
and then you'll go ahead and do whatever you were going to do anyway
到最後還是把我的話完全拋在腦後
without having heard a word I've said.
一走了之
What?
你說什麼
Am I just supposed to stand here
我是不是應該接受
and accept these obvious signs that you have gone mad?
你已經瘋掉的事實然後袖手旁觀？
It's my old pup tent. What do you think?
這是我的舊帳篷，你覺得怎麼樣？
Well, I think it's the perfect place for you to spend the night.
我覺得你今晚在這裏過夜最合適不過
You realize we all think this is a terrible idea, right?
你知道所有人都覺得這是個餿主意，是嗎？
It's certainly been brought to my attention.
你們確實讓我感受到了
- But you're still going to do it? - Yes.
- 但你還是要干？ - 不錯
It's just kinda insane, Dad. The whole thing, at your age?
這真的有點神經，爸，你都這麼老了還搞這些？
Fit people in their 20's can't do it, Dad.
二十幾歲的年輕小伙子都做不到，老爸
It takes five months and five millions steps.
這要花五個月的時間和走五百萬步的路
- Of walking. - Yes.
- 走路啊 - 是啊
I've been doing it for a while, you know.
我可是經常走路的
Dad, hiking is not walking.
爸，徒步旅行可不是走路這麼簡單
Two thousand people a year try to do this. Less than 10% make it.
每年都有兩千人嘗試但只有不到10%的人成功
You ought to see the statistics on how many people finish writing a book.
你真該研究一下有多少人能堅持寫完一本書
There's somebody I want you to meet. All right?
我想讓你見個人，好嗎？
Hey, Dave.
嗨，戴維
How's it going?
最近還好吧？
This is Dave.
這位是戴維
- Dave. - Hello.
- 戴維 - 你好
He has hiked everywhere.
他徒步過的地方遍佈世界
He can answer any question you have about anything.
他能解答你的任何疑問
Okay. Can he tell me why the caged bird sings?
好啊，那他能不能告訴我，為什麼籠子裏的鳥會唱歌？
Can you give us just a second? And can I?
給我們點時間，能不能借一步？
Can we keep a lid on the jokes, please?
咱們能不能先不開玩笑？拜託了
Pay attention while he's talking,
認真聽他講話
and don't say, "You've got to be shitting me"
在他告訴你價格的時候
when he tells you the price of something.
別說「你是在逗我嗎」
Sam, you act like I've never camped before.
山姆，你說的我好像從來沒露營過一樣
A tent is a tent.
帳篷就是帳篷
This also has a 70 denier, high-density, abrasion-resistant fly
這一款纖度是70，高密度，超耐磨
with that same rip stop weave.
採用了相同的防撕裂編織法
And just look at these seams.
來看看這些接縫
All lap-felled. No bias taping on the whole tent.
全都是雙折邊疊縫，整個帳篷完全沒有斜裁帶
And the poles. Color-coded, DAC aluminum.
還有支架，都是顏色編碼，數字解碼鋁材料
It's the finest craftsmanship.
這可是最精良的工藝
Yeah, I've carried this one on several sections of the trail myself.
我自己旅途中也多次用到了這玩意
For your purposes, cannot go wrong with this monster.
對你來說，這個小怪獸不會錯
All right, how much is it?
好吧，多少錢？
This one here is 289.
這個是289美元
You've got to be shitting... Oh, okay.
你是在逗…哦，好吧
I see what you're thinking, but out on the trail, you're gonna thank me.
我懂你的想法，但你上路之後會感謝我的
Are you coming?
你也要一起？
You'll need a rain cover too, of course.
當然，你還需要一個防雨布
- A rain cover? Why? - To keep out the rain.
- 防雨布？幹嘛用？ - 用來防雨
- The backpacks aren't waterproof? - Not 100%.
- 這背包不防水嗎？ - 不是100%防水
The rain cover weighs four point six ounces.
防雨布重約130克
You know how much weight it would add to fully waterproof an 85-liter pack?
你知道一個完全防水的85升包要比這重多少？
Well, I'll tell you. It's a lot.
告訴你吧，重得多了
Let's not forget...
不要忘記這個…
Oh, let me guess, in case you want to do a little impromptu gardening?
讓我猜猜，以防突然想做點園藝活兒？
No. You know the saying, "Take only memories, leave only footprints".
不，你知道有個說法叫 "帶走的只有回憶，留下的只有足跡"
Poop.
糞便
- Oh, shit. - Exactly.
- 屎啊 - 沒錯
Thought you'd find these interesting.
覺得你可能需要看看這些
A Virginia man's remains left undiscovered for 18 days
佐治亞州的一個人在獨自上路的一周後
after he suffers a catastrophic medical condition
遭遇了極為嚴重的健康狀況
just one week into his solo trek.
至今已失蹤18天
Most commonly spread through infected rodent saliva, urine, and feces,
最普遍的傳播方式 是受感染的齧齒動物的唾液，尿液和糞便
which become airborne particles...
變成空氣中傳播的微粒…
Several law enforcement personnel have expressed concern
多名執法人員表示了
about the gruesome nature of these latest murders,
對近來發生的謀殺案的擔憂
including dismemberment and ritualistic savagery.
包含肢解以及殘忍的獻祭儀式
You are not doing this alone.
你不能獨自上路
This is Bryson.
我是布萊森
How would you like to join me for a little stroll?
你有沒有興趣和我一起去散散心？
It's a chance to grab some fresh air, while there's still some left.
可以趁著還有新鮮空氣的時候多呼吸一些
You know, studies show Americans need to walk more.
研究表明，美國人需要多走路
Our forefathers, they walked everywhere.
我們的祖先們可哪都跑遍了
It'll give you something to do for the next six months.
我來告訴你接下來的六個月可以做些什麼
Let me know if you're interested.
感興趣的話就聯繫我
Rabies, crazed skunks, raccoons, and squirrels,
狂犬病，發狂的臭鼬，浣熊和松鼠
merciless fire ants, and ravening blackfly.
無情的火蟻，貪婪的墨蚊
Poison ivy, poison sumac, poison oak,
劇毒藤條，劇毒漆樹，劇毒橡樹
poison salamanders, even a scattering of moose?
劇毒蠑螈，甚至是散佈的麋鹿
Not in this lifetime.
這輩子都不可能
I wish I could, Bill, but I just switched to a new beta blocker.
我也想去，比爾，但我剛開始用新的降壓藥
I barely have enough energy
我沒有足夠的精力
to get dressed in the...
去穿上…
Next time, call me for something fun.
下次最好叫我做點好玩的事
Like a colonoscopy.
比如結腸鏡檢查
Bill, I think you've been the victim of identity theft.
比爾，我想你的身份可能被盜用了
I got the most ridiculous message
我收到一條特別荒唐的消息
from someone claiming...
那人聲稱…
Bill, you know you can see the whole trail online in less than four minutes?
比爾，你難道不知道 在網上花不到四分鐘就能看到整個山路？
You know, you can't count Dan Budge. Dying is not the same as saying no.
你不能算上丹·布吉，去世和拒絕可不一樣
Did we know about that? About Dan's death?
我們知道這事嗎？丹的過世？
Yeah, I think it was in Janice's Christmas card.
對啊，我記得詹尼斯的聖誕卡上寫了
Well, that explains why she was so miffed about my invitation.
怪不得她對我的邀請這麼惱怒
It's in the...
在那裏
Hello?
喂？
Hey, it's me.
嗨，是我
I'm sorry?
你哪位？
Bryson, it's Katz.
布萊森，我是凱茲
- It's Katz? - Yeah.
- 凱茲 - 沒錯
- Stephen?
- 史蒂芬？ - 是的
You're in the States?
你在美國嗎？
Yeah, yeah. Where are you?
對，是的，你在哪？
I'm in Des Moines. Where the hell else would I be?
我在得梅因，還能在哪？
Well, it's good to hear your voice.
很高興聽到你的聲音
Yeah. Hey, Doug told me about this Appalachian Trail deal of yours.
道格告訴我你想去阿帕拉契山道旅行
Are you serious about that?
你是認真的嗎？
Yes, I'm very serious.
沒錯，我非常認真
You think maybe I could come with you?
你覺得我能不能陪你去？
You wanna come with me?
你想和我一起？
Yeah, if it's a problem, I understand.
對啊，如果不方便的話，我也能理解
- No, no, no, no. - I mean, I understand if you don't want me.
- 不，不，不，不 - 你要是不想要我的話我能理解
No, why... Why wouldn't I want you?
不，我…我為什麼不想要你？
Because, you know, I still owe you 600 bucks from Europe.
因為，你在歐洲借我的600塊我還沒還呢
Well, that was forty years ago, Stephen.
那都是四十年前的事了，史蒂芬
Yeah, but I still intend to pay you.
是，但我還是想還給你
Well, I know you're good for it.
我知道你會做到的
Ah, great, great.
好吧，好吧
So, what kind of shape you in?
你身體怎麼樣？
Well, I'm in good shape. I walk everywhere these days.
我身體挺好的，最近我去哪都步行
Really?
真的嗎？
Yeah, since the bastards took away my license.
是啊，自從那些王八蛋吊銷了我的駕照
So, how are you with bears?
你和熊相處的如何？
Well, they haven't gotten me yet.
它們還沒找到我呢
Well, you know there can't be a black bear within 1,500 miles of Des Moines, Katz.
得梅因方圓1,500英里內是不會有黑熊的，凱茲
That's what I'm saying, man. Those fuckers keep their distance.
說的沒錯，那幫狗日的離得遠著呢
You'll never guess who just gave me a call.
你絕對猜不到誰剛剛來電話了
No, no, no. Not Stephen Katz.
不，不，不，不能是史蒂芬·凱茲
You said I couldn't go alone.
是你說我不能單獨上路的
Well, presuming you were going to get somebody responsible.
我是說你得找個靠譜的人陪你一起
You don't even know him.
你都不認識他
Well, I know the stories. Didn't he have a drinking problem?
我知道他的事跡，他不是酗酒嗎？
We all had drinking problems.
我們都曾酗酒
Well, you two ended up on each other's nerves in Europe.
你們倆最終在歐洲鬧得很不愉快
No, no, no, no. We started out on each other's nerves.
不，不，不，不，我們開始就很不愉快
We ended up despising each other.
最終相互鄙視
You know I hate this, right?
你知道我討厭這樣，不是嗎？
Sweetheart, I really don't think you have anything to worry about.
親愛的，我真的不覺得你有什麼好擔心的
No. Just my husband wandering off into the woods,
是啊，不就是我丈夫要去林子裏晃蕩
surely to be maimed or killed
幾乎可以肯定會受傷甚至死亡
or contract some ghastly parasitic disease which,
或感染些可怕的寄生病
if lucky, will leave him propped up in a chair, drooling into his own bib.
幸運的話，可能他還有機會癱在輪椅上流口水
But there's nothing to worry about, because of course
但這沒什麼好擔心的，因為我肯定是
I'll be the one expected to stand by your side, feeding you ice chips
那個留在你身邊，餵你冰片的人
until you capitulate to this unnamed malady, and then what?
直到你向這個天知道是什麼的病魔投降，然後呢？
I get to stand in front of some gaudy church saying,
我得站在某個浮誇的教堂說
"He was a loving husband and father,"
"他曾是仁愛的丈夫和父親"
"once considered to be a man of reasonable intelligence,"
"在事實證明他是一個十足的"
"since revealed to be nothing more"
"可笑的傻瓜之前"
"than a daft and utter fool."
"還算是個明智的人"
Well, it's a shame I won't be there to hear it.
真可惜我沒法親耳聽到
Look, I know what this seems like, okay?
聽著，我明白這看上去很荒唐
Have you actually thought this through at all?
你到底有沒有認認真真地考慮過這個問題
Of course not.
當然沒有
Lebanon Airport welcomes Cape Air Flight 106.
歡迎海角航空公司106號航班來到黎巴嫩機場
Travelers arriving from Springfield
來自斯普林菲爾德的旅客
can claim their baggage at Baggage Claim Carousel Four.
可在四號傳送台取回行李
You are shitting me.
你他媽逗我呢
- Hey, Stephen. - Bryson.
- 嗨，史蒂芬 - 布萊森
How are you?
你好嗎？
Hello, Steve-o.
你好，老史
This is my wife.
這位是我妻子
You're the British nurse I've heard so much about.
您一定就是那位英國護士，久仰久仰
- I certainly hope so. - Yeah.
- 希望久仰的不是別的護士 - 沒錯
Good to meet you.
很高興見到你
That's a little bit like a bear hug.
剛那個有點像熊抱
Are you limping?
你瘸了嗎？
Oh, that's a titanium knee, and this one's a trick knee, you know.
哦，這是鈦合金膝蓋，這是個假膝蓋
- Oh. - Let me see, I've got to get...
- 哦 - 讓我想想，我得要去…
I gotta eat every hour or so, otherwise I get these, uh...
我每個小時都要進食，不然的話我就會…
- What, episodes? - No, no, they're...
- 怎樣？抽風？ - 不對，不是，這叫…
- Seizures? - Seizures, that's right.
- 痙攣？ - 痙攣，沒錯
- You get seizures? - Mmm-hmm.
- 你會痙攣？ - 恩
Yeah. You know, I ate some contaminated phenethylamines about 10 years ago,
是的，大概十年前我吃了受污染的苯乙胺
and it totally jacked up my system, you know.
把我的身體徹底搞垮了
- I thought you said you were in shape? - I am.
- 你不是說你身體挺好的嗎？ - 是挺好啊
So the two of them take off on a motorbike
這倆個傢伙就騎著摩托車出發了
and we have no choice but to hitchhike all the way back to San Sebastian.
我們不得不一路搭便車到聖塞瓦斯蒂安
We go into the first pub, and boom, there they are.
我們進到第一家酒館，他們就在那！
So, six hours later we stumble out to the beach,
六個小時之後，我們蹣跚來到了沙灘上
and Bryson insists on having the pretty girl,
而布萊森一定要要那個漂亮姑娘
- of course, the redhead. - Ooh.
當然了，是紅頭髮
And I get the horse-faced blonde, you know.
而我的則是一個馬臉的金髮妞
Uh, Bryson!
布萊森！
I can't believe... Come on, sit.
真不敢相信，快來坐下
I can't believe you never told Cathy about Spain.
真不敢相信你居然從未和凱西提起過西班牙
Oh, it must have slipped my mind.
我肯定是忘記了
Hmm, I wonder why?
這是為什麼呢？
Anyway, the next day we're on a train to Madrid.
總而言之，第二天，我們上了去馬德里的火車
Bryson goes to the head and I don't pay any attention to it,
布萊森去了車頭，而我壓根就沒注意
and he's in there a long time.
他在那待了好一會
Finally, I look up, and he's coming out toward the seat
最後，我一抬頭，發現他正向他的座位走去
and he's just scratching and scratching...
而且一直在撓一直在撓
Got it. Got it.
我懂了，我懂了
I said to him, "Hey, Bryson, what's going on?"
我問他「布萊森，你怎麼回事？」
And he says, "Next time you can have the red-head".
他說「下次紅頭髮的讓給你」
- Is there a picture of the red-head? - I think so.
- 有紅頭髮的照片嗎？ - 應該吧
I'd like to see the redhead. I'd love to see the red-head.
我想看看她長什麼樣，我想看看她的紅頭髮
- That's a really great story. - She's not in here.
- 這故事真棒 - 她不在這裏面
- Thank you for sharing that with my family. Where is she?
- 非常感謝你能和我的家人分享 - 她在哪？
Well, I have more of them, Bryson.
我還有更多故事，布萊森
No, no, that's great.
不用，不用了，這就挺好
- No, no, I think we should have a few more. - All right.
- 不，不，我覺得咱們得再聽幾個 - 好吧
We were in Nice, and Bryson goes to this
我們在尼斯的時候，布萊森去了一個
very famous hotel there called The Mayflower...
非常著名的酒店叫做五月花…
Mmm, the Cubbies.
卡比隊
Oh, decomposed.
在阿帕拉契山上發現腐爛屍體
Oh, my God.
熊襲擊了一對年輕夫婦
You still playing that thing?
你還一直在吹這玩意？
Oh, yeah. Not good, but I'm playing.
是的，不算好，但是在吹
How about you, still playing the drums?
你呢，還打鼓嗎？
Oh, God, no. I gave that up years ago.
早就不了
Is that your daughter?
那是你女兒嗎？
- Yeah. - Takes after her mother. Lucky break there.
- 是 - 隨她母親，可真幸運
- How many grandchildren in all? - Three, and another one on the way.
- 你一共有幾個孫子？ - 三個，不過馬上還要再添一個
You really pulled it off, Bryson.
你真是人生贏家啊，布萊森
No, I mean that. I'm happy for you.
我是說，我真為你感到高興
Well, how about you, Stephen? You... You been okay?
你呢，史蒂芬？你…你還好吧？
Me? Oh, hell, yeah.
我？當然好了
I spent half my life getting drunk, chasing pussy.
半輩子都在燈紅酒綠，泡著小妞
The other half I wasted.
另外半輩子也都浪費了
- Have you seen these things? - Yeah.
- 你有看這些嗎？ - 看了
Fucked.
真操蛋
Hey, you know,
知道嗎
everyone thinks we're going to go onto that trail
所有人都覺得咱們倆的旅行
and quit after a week, like most people do.
肯定像大部分人一樣，一周後就不幹了
We're not most people, Bryson.
咱們不是大部分人，布萊森
No. No, we're not.
不，不，咱們可不是
- So, good night. - Good night.
- 晚安吧 - 晚安
All right then.
就這樣吧
- Thank you, Mrs. Bryson. Bye. - You're welcome. Good luck.
- 非常感謝，布萊森夫人，再會 - 不客氣，祝你好運
I'll meet you inside. Right?
我在裏面等你，好吧？
- I will miss you, you know. - I hope so.
- 你知道我會想你的 - 希望如此
I just want to go on the record one last time
我就想再和你說最後一次
and say, I do love you.
我愛你
Try not to die, okay?
盡量別死掉，好嗎？
I'll do my best.
我盡力而為
Go on. Bugger off.
走吧，趕緊走
I remember this one guy that I picked up. He came off the Trail.
我記得我載過的一個人，他走完了全程
He's not like you guys, a lot younger.
不像你們，他年輕多了
He got back there and just started crying.
他坐到後面然後就開始哭
I'm serious. Cried all the way back to Atlanta.
沒說笑，他一路哭到了亞特蘭大
Sat back there whimpering like a child.
坐在後面哭的像個小孩
When you drop people off,
當你把人送到地方時
can you tell whether they're going to make it or not?
你就能判斷他們會不會成功嗎？
Oh. Yes, sir, yes, sir. Every time, pretty near.
可以，先生，可以的，每次都八九不離十
How about us?
你覺得我倆呢？
Oh, well, here we are.
哦，咱們到了
Thank you.
謝謝
- Here you go. - Okay.
- 給你 - 好的
- Breakfast at seven. - Seven.
- 早餐七點開始 - 七點
- Yeah. Okay. - Okay.
- 好的 - 沒問題
I hope you don't mind my saying,
希望你不介意我的說法
but these are about the best damn pancakes I ever had.
這煎餅是我吃過最他媽好吃的
Is that right? Well, I like a man who appreciates his pancakes.
是嗎？我喜歡會品味煎餅的人
Well, I sure do appreciate these, honey.
沒有錯，寶貝
- Would you like some coffee? - Yeah.
- 需要咖啡嗎？ - 好
And I'll get you a menu.
我去給你拿菜單
No, no, I've already eaten. Thanks.
不，不用了，我已經吃過了，謝謝
Not bad looking, huh?
長得不賴，是吧？
That depends.
這得看情況
You know what I look for in a female these days?
你知道我現在看中女人的哪些方面嗎？
A heartbeat and a full set of limbs.
四肢健全的活人
Well, most people lower their standards as they age.
大多數人都會隨著年齡增長降低標準
- Yeah? - You've actually raised yours.
- 是嗎？ - 而你卻把標準提高了
You know, Bryson, I've been thinking.
布萊森，我在想
Let's stay here another night.
咱們再在這待一晚吧
- You kidding? - No. No. It is cold outside.
- 你逗我？ - 不，不，外面太冷了
It's warm in here.
這裏很暖和
- I am going. - Wait a minute.
- 我先走了 - 等一下
We go. We go.
咱們走，咱們走
Hey, hang on. I'd like to say a few words if you don't mind.
等等，你不介意的話我想說兩句
All right.
好啊
- I don't want to reach for metaphors, but... - No, reach, Bryson, reach.
- 我不想打比喻，但是… - 別這樣，打吧，布萊森，打吧
Well, they say the Appalachian Trail is like life.
人們說，阿帕裏奇山脈就像人生
You don't know what's ahead, you don't know what's going to happen next,
你不知道前方是什麼，也不知道下一刻會發生什麼
but you give it your best shot.
但你得竭盡全力
Your best...
竭盡…
So, on that note...
既然如此…
- We go? - We go.
- 咱們上路？ - 上路
All right.
好吧
You keeping up?
你還跟得上吧？
Yeah. Keeping up.
跟得上
Are we hiking or strolling?
咱們是在徒步還是在晃悠？
What, is this a race?
怎麼？這還要比賽嗎？
We're trying to do 11 miles.
咱們要走11英里
Slow and steady, pal. You wanna burn out your legs, go ahead.
一步一個腳印，老兄 你要是想走壞你的腿，那隨你便
- Just be nice to get there before midnight. - Yeah, well.
- 最好能趕在午夜前到 - 是，是
That would be nice.
那樣最好
Go ahead. Help yourselves.
你們先走，請隨意
Oh, jeez.
哦，天吶
Okay, complete the following sentence.
完成以下句子
What goes up must come
凡是上去的都得要
down.
下來
What the hell happened to down? It can't be uphill all the way to Maine.
怎麼還沒見到下坡？ 不可能到緬因的路全都是上坡
Coming through.
借過
Oh, my God. All right.
天吶，好吧
- What's up? - Not much.
- 你好嗎？ - 還好
- Beautiful day. - Yeah, it sure is.
- 天氣真好 - 是啊，確實很好
- Excuse me. - Okay.
- 借過 - 好的
Little fuckers.
這幫熊孩子
It's just over the hill, guys.
翻過這山坡就到了，孩子們
- Boy. - You okay?
- 天吶 - 你還好嗎？
Yeah. I almost fell off the log.
還好，我差點掉下去了
How far do you figure we've gone?
你覺得咱們走了多遠？
Oh, about a quarter of a mile.
差不多四分之一英里
Motherfuck.
操他媽的
We're going already?
這就要走了？
Just kill me now.
殺了我吧
I don't care how you do it, but please, just kill me now.
不管你用什麼手段，求你，殺了我吧
What, that's it? No dinner?
怎麼，這就睡？不吃點了？
Hiya.
你好
- You remember the Randall Farm? - Of course.
- 還記得蘭德爾農場嗎？ - 當然
Super-Walmart now.
現在變成沃爾瑪了
Christ.
老天
The old drive-in theater?
那汽車電影院呢？
Don't tell me.
還是別告訴我了
- Subaru dealership now. - No.
- 變成斯巴魯經銷商了 - 不是吧
Yeah. I got my first blowjob there.
沒錯，我第一次的口活就是在那
In the Subaru dealership?
在斯巴魯經銷商？
Bit of a late bloomer, huh?
有點晚了，不是嗎？
I bumped into Jimmy Duncan a few weeks back.
幾周前我偶然碰到了吉米·鄧肯
You remember him?
你還記得他嗎？
Yeah. His mom worked at the library?
記得，他媽媽在圖書館工作
'Course you remember his mom.
你當然記得他媽了
Yeah, she was nice.
對啊，她人挺好
And she didn't own a bra.
而且還沒有胸罩
Well, if she did, she never wore it.
即便有也從來沒穿過
Man, I loved that library.
我愛死那個圖書館了
- Hey, Bryson? - Yeah?
- 布萊森 - 怎麼了？
Have you really kept in touch with Doug Glawinski all these years?
你這些年有沒有和道格·格萊文斯基聯繫過？
No, not at all. Why?
沒，從來沒有，怎麼了？
You invited him, so I was just curious.
你邀請他了，我只是好奇
Well, yeah. I invited everyone I could think of.
對啊，我邀請了我能想到的所有人
No, not everyone.
不，不是所有人
I heard about it from Doug.
我是從道格那裏聽說的
I don't think I had your number.
我沒有你的號碼
You had Doug's number?
你有道格的號碼？
Well, if it makes you feel any better, I really don't like Doug.
我很不喜歡道格，如果這麼說能讓你好受點的話
Well, I don't blame you.
我不是在怪你
I'm not sure how that's supposed to make me feel better, though.
雖然我不懂這怎麼會讓我好受
Yeah.
是啊
I guess I really didn't think that through.
就當我剛剛講話沒經腦子吧
Good night.
晚安
You burying your shit?
你在埋屎嗎？
Yes.
是的
- In the woods? - Yeah.
- 在森林裏？ - 沒錯
Oh, Bryson, I've missed you.
哦，布萊森，我想死你了
Thank you.
謝謝
Can't wait to read about this in the book.
等不及在你的書中讀到這段了
I'm not writing a book.
我不打算寫書
Hi.
你好
You guys camping here?
你們在這露營？
No, we live here.
不，我們就住這
What are you guys eating?
你們在吃什麼？
Noodles? Ugh, big mistake.
麵條？啊，你犯了個大錯誤
Noodles have got, like, no energy in them. I mean, like, zero.
麵條裏面可沒有能量，完全沒有
I'm Mary Ellen. Is that your tent?
我是瑪麗·艾倫，那是你的帳篷？
Yeah.
是的
Oh, big mistake.
哦，又是個大錯誤
They must have seen you coming at the camping store.
你肯定是在露營用品店買的
- How much did you pay for it? - I don't remember.
- 你花了多少錢？ - 我不記得了
Too much. That's how much.
很多錢，對不對
Shoulda got a three-season tent, my friend.
你應該買個三季帳篷，朋友
It is a three-season tent.
這就是個三季帳篷
Pardon me for saying so, but it is, like, seriously dumb
請原諒我這麼講，但三月份出來露營
to come out here in March without a three-season tent.
還不帶個三季帳篷，真的很愚蠢
It's April. And it is a three-season tent.
現在是四月，而且這就是個三季帳篷
That's a three-season tent.
這才是三季帳篷
No, no. Those are both three-season tents.
不，不，這倆都是三季帳篷
No. I don't think so.
不，我不這麼認為
How many miles did you guys do today?
你們今天走了多少英里？
Around 10.
差不多10英里吧
Ten? Oh, you must be really out of shape.
十英里？你們的身體不行啊
I did fourteen-two. Started at Gooch Gap.
我走了14.2英里，從古奇驛站出發的
Well, so did we. And it's eight point four.
我們也是，只有8.4英里
- No. - It is. It's eight point four.
- 胡說 - 沒錯，就只有8.4英里
Excuse me. But I think I ought to know. I just walked it.
抱歉，但我從那裏走來，我知道我走了多遠
So did we. And it's eight point four.
我們也從那裏走來，而這只有8.4英里
Tomato, tomahto.
隨你怎麼說
You know what your problem is?
你知道你的問題出在哪嗎？
You're too fat.
你太胖了
Excuse me?
你說什麼？
You should have dropped some of that tonnage before you hit the trailhead.
你應該在上路前減點肥
I mean, you're liable to have some sort of serious heart thing out here.
你很可能在外面突發個心臟病什麼的
And so I just walk alone, because everybody I know is boring.
所以我就獨自上路了，因為我認識的人都太無聊了
I'm the only person I know who doesn't bore myself to death.
我認識的唯一一個不會無聊透頂的人就是我自己
Also, if I walked with someone else,
而且，如果我和其他人一起徒步的話
I'd have to watch them make, you know, mistake after mistake after mistake,
我就得眼睜睜看著他們接連犯錯誤
and I'd go crazy, and then I'd not be sane on the trail, you know?
那我就會抓狂，就會失去理智
I was like, "Mary Ellen, who's the only person you know"
我會問「瑪麗·艾倫，你認識的唯一一個」
"who doesn't mess up?" and it's like, me.
「不會把事情搞砸的人是誰？」答案就是我
I went through this person, it was, like, dumb.
我遇到一個人，太蠢了
That person, boring. This person, dumb. Dumb, dumb. Boring, boring.
又遇到一個人，太無聊 這個人蠢，蠢，蠢，無聊，無聊
I know what you're thinking. I'm not married.
我知道你們在想什麼，我還未婚
I wonder why?
真想知道為什麼
Well, I do have a boyfriend, but he's in Florida and he's in prison.
我倒是有個男朋友，但他在弗羅裏達蹲監獄呢
I wouldn't hike with him even if he wasn't
即便他不在監獄我也不會和他徒步
because you can't trust a convict, and he's dumb.
因為你不能信任罪犯，而且他很蠢
And boring, actually.
事實上也很無聊
What's your star sign? I bet you're a Gemini, aren't you?
你什麼星座？我猜你是雙子座，對嗎？
Ah, I'm really good at this. I have a gift.
我很擅長這個，這是我的天賦
- No, I'm not a Gemini. - I think you are.
- 不，我不是雙子座 - 我覺得你就是
Actually, I'm a Leo.
事實上我是獅子座
I don't think so. I'm really good at this.
我不覺得是，我很擅長這個的
I was born in August.
我八月份出生的
Mmm, check your birth certificate.
好好檢查一下你的出生證
And you? You're a Libra.
你呢？你是天秤座吧
Definitely a Libra. I could make a living doing this.
肯定是天秤座，我都能以此謀生了
You're zero for two, honey. Zero for two.
你兩猜零中，寶貝，兩猜零中
Can you guys guess what I am?
你們能猜到我是什麼座嗎？
- Couple of thoughts come to mind. - Yeah?
- 倒是有點想法 - 真的？
She's up all night to the sun.
她通宵狂歡，直到太陽升起
I'm up all night to get some.
我徹夜未眠，尋歡作樂
She's up all night for good fun.
她徹夜不睡，玩鬧嬉笑
We're up all night to get lucky.
我徹夜不睡，等待艷遇
Fuck.
操
God damn it. Damn it!
操他娘的，操他娘！
I swear to God I'm gonna rip her larynx out.
我發誓我要撕爛她的喉嚨
I'm not sure that's going to do it. I got a better plan.
別說這沒用的，我有個更好的計劃
Go on, lay it on me.
快點，告訴我
Okay, according to the map, we get to Hiawassee tomorrow.
根據地圖，咱們明天抵達海亞瓦夕
We get an early start and we hike hard, we can put some distance between us.
咱們早點出發，拚命走，和她拉開距離
Yeah, that's probably better than my plan.
好，這比我的計劃好
What's your plan?
你的計劃是什麼
Kill her. Take her Pop-tarts.
殺了她，帶走她的餅乾
- Hey, good morning. - Good morning.
- 嗨，早安 - 早上好
You guys heading out?
你們要出發了？
Yeah. You want us to wait for you?
是啊，要我們等你嗎？
Yeah, we'll wait.
我們可以等你
Nah, I'll catch up. I'm pretty regular.
不用，我會趕上的，我很規律
We go.
咱們快走
We've still got a couple more miles.
咱們還得多走幾英里
How far back is she?
甩了她多遠？
She's gaining.
她趕上來了
- I don't think... - I don't...
- 我不覺得… - 我不…
We need a new plan.
咱們需要新計劃
- Yeah, we do. We need a new plan. - Yeah.
- 是的，咱們需要新計劃 - 沒錯
Shh.
噓
I didn't say anything.
我什麼都沒說
- Well, you sound like a DC-10. Keep it down. - Oh.
- 你聲音大的跟飛機一樣，小聲點 - 哦
Here she comes.
她來了
Hold your breath.
屏住呼吸
Hold it, hold it.
屏住，屏住
We've come too far to give up who we are.
要想改變本性早已來不及
We go, we go!
咱們走，咱們走！
Wait, stop!
等等，停車！
Who the hell's gonna stop for us? We look like shit.
誰他媽會給咱倆停車？咱倆這麼挫
Hey, stop!
嘿，停車！
They stopped!
他們停了！
Hey, you boys want a ride?
小伙子們要搭車嗎？
Sure do!
必須的！
Y'all have to excuse us. We are celebrating.
原諒我們，我們在慶祝
Yeah? What are you celebrating?
是嗎？慶祝什麼？
We are getting married tomorrow.
我們明天要結婚了
- Great, great. - Congratulations, you guys.
- 真好，真好 - 恭喜二位
Yeah, Darren is making an honest woman out of me.
是啊，達倫讓我的身體變誠實
- Ain't that right, baby? - Yes, I am.
- 不是嗎，寶貝？ - 是啊
Uh, you wanna watch the...
啊，你們應該看著…
Yeah.
就這樣
Holy shit. I wish I was still 20.
幹他娘，真希望我還是20歲
I wish I was still 50.
我希望我還是50歲
See y'all later. Bye, y'all.
- 兩位再見 - 再會二位
What can I get you boys to drink?
二位需要喝點什麼嗎？
The tallest and the coldest beer you can offer.
你們這最冰量最大的啤酒
Coke.
可樂
- Just Coke, nothing in it? - Just Coke. I'm reformed.
- 只是可樂，不加點什麼？ - 可樂就好，我改過自新了
- Okay. - Uh, you know what?
- 好的 - 我改一下
Make mine a Coke also.
我也只要可樂好了
All right. Just a second.
好的，馬上就好
Oh, wow. I'm... I'm impressed.
我…我很佩服你啊
Well, you know, ever since I rolled my car on route six,
你懂的，自從我在路上翻了車
- I had to rethink some things. - Yeah, that'll do it.
- 我得重新思考一些問題 - 是啊，這挺管用
A lady cop came up to the window and she knocked.
一個女警敲了敲我的車窗
I was hanging upside down by the seatbelt and I said, "What's the problem, officer?"
我被安全帶倒吊著說「有什麼問題嗎？警官」
She just stared at me and walked away.
她瞪了我一眼然後走開了
So I haven't had a drink since.
從那以後我再沒喝過酒
- Really? - Yeah.
- 真的？ - 是的
Well, that's good.
那挺不錯的
- Good for you. - Yeah. Good for me.
- 對你有好處 - 是啊，對我很有好處
Really.
確實
You know, Bryson,
布萊森
I keep looking at the door over there and I keep seeing Mary Ellen coming through.
我一直盯著門口，總覺得瑪麗·艾倫會走進來
I hope you're not going to tell me you miss her?
可別告訴我你很想她
Oh, no, no. Hell no, I'm not going to tell you that.
不，不，才不是，我不是這個意思
I mean, we did kind of ditch her though, didn't we?
我是說，某種程度上講咱們的確甩了她，不是嗎？
No, we didn't just kind of ditch her, Stephen. We ditched her.
不對，不是某種程度講我們甩了她 我們的的確確是甩了她
Yeah. We left her all alone in the woods by herself.
是啊，我們把她獨自一人丟在森林裏
She came into the woods by herself.
是她自己獨自一人來到森林裏
It's not like we signed a contract to look after her.
我們又不是簽了合同要照顧她
No, but she's probably scared out of her wits.
沒錯，但她可能嚇壞了
What are you so interested in her for?
你幹嘛對她這麼上心？
I'm not interested in her at all.
我不是對她上心
The damndest thing, Bryson, is I am a Libra.
可惡的是，我就是天秤座的
She got it right.
她說對了
Maybe she has a gift.
或許她真的有天賦
What are the chances?
這概率才多少？
One in 12, actually.
實際上有十二分之一
One in 12. That's pretty damn good.
十二分之一，那還真不賴
Oh. Southbound, coming through.
向南前進
Mary Ellen? Oh, yeah, she talked about you guys.
瑪麗·艾倫？沒錯，她提起過你們
Yeah? What did she say?
是嗎？她說了什麼？
- Well, her words, right? - Right.
- 她的原話，對吧 - 沒錯
She said you guys were a couple of overweight wimps
她說你們是兩個對徒步旅行一無所知
who didn't know the first thing about hiking.
而且超重的廢物
And she was tired of carrying you.
她受夠了帶著你們
Oh, Holy Christ Almighty.
哦，我的老天
Actually, I think she called you a couple of pussies.
事實上，她說你們是兩個老娘們
- Pussies?
- 老娘們？
After all we did for her?
我們還幫了她那麼多？
You guys know it's supposed to snow tonight, right? Six to eight inches.
你們知道今晚會下雪嗎？六到八英吋高
- Really? - More higher up.
- 真的嗎？ - 或許更高
That's what they're saying. You're going to be climbing right into it.
人們都這麼說，你們就要爬進冰雪的懷抱
- Yeah? Oh. - Yeah.
- 真的？ - 是的
- Well, I gotta keep moving, guys. Be safe. - Thanks.
- 好了，我該上路了，哥們，注意安全 - 謝謝
Snow? That guy's out of his fucking mind.
下雪？那傢伙瘋了吧
You okay?
你還好嗎？
Never better.
從沒這麼好過
Goddamn things are useless.
這些破玩意屁用不頂
What I'm thinking we could do is follow this logging road,
我覺得咱們能做的是沿著這條伐木道
get to the other side of this ridge, and get out of the wind
走到山脊的另一側避開風
where we can set up our camp. What do you think?
在那咱們搭起帳篷，你覺得呢？
Me? I think I'd rather have a nice hot soak in a Jacuzzi.
我？我覺得我更願意泡個熱水澡
But if you're dead-set on following that logging road, we can do that, too.
但如果你決心要走這條伐木道也行
We can save the Jacuzzi for another time when things aren't going so well.
咱們可以把熱水澡留到下次諸事不順的時候
Yeah.
好的
- I'll follow you. - Okay.
- 我跟在你後面 - 好的
Katz, you still there?
凱茲，你還在嗎？
Unfortunately.
可惜還在
Just like you said, Bryson.
正如你所說，布萊森
The AT. You never know what lies ahead.
在阿帕拉契山脈，你永遠不知道會發生什麼
So it appears.
就這麼出現了
I promise you, if there was heat, it would be on, honey, all right?
我保證，如果有暖氣的話，一定打開，好嗎？
Use the talcum powder, that helps.
抹點爽身粉，會有幫助的
Hi. We'd like a cabin. Preferably with a private bath.
你好，我們需要一間屋子，最好有私人浴室
The cabins went two days ago. But I do have two spaces in the bunkhouse.
屋子兩天前都沒了，但大房裏還有兩個位置
I don't know if you're aware of this, Bryson,
不知道你有沒有意識到，布萊森
but every time I hear the word "bunkhouse"
但每當我聽到"大房"這個詞
my testicles shrink up inside my body.
我都會蛋蛋一緊
Welcome to the Stalag.
歡迎來到戰俘營
There's a meeting of the Escape Committee at 1900 hours.
逃亡委員會的會議於下午七點鐘開始
Oh, okay.
哦，得了吧
Hey, are you liking that XT-85?
你喜歡那個XT-85嗎？
Your pack.
你的背包
- I got a Gregory. - Oh, yeah?
- 我買的是格裏戈雷 - 是嗎？
Yeah. I looked at the XT-85, solid pack.
是的，我就盯著XT-85，看著很結實
But the quad access points,
但有人指出
dual hydration ports in the Gregory, they sold me.
格裏戈雷的那個雙水管的包 他們就賣給了我
What made you buy an XT-85?
你為什麼買了XT-85？
I thought it was easier than carrying everything in my arms.
我覺得這比用手抱著東西方便
- How come you're up top? - Well, heat rises, pal.
- 你怎麼在上面？ - 熱氣往上升啊，老兄
Oh, yeah.
好了
Hey, you know...
你知道嗎…
Hey, Bryson, are you all right?
嘿，布萊森，你還好嗎？
Oh, never better.
從未如此好過
We can start, maybe, right there and...
咱們可以從那裏開始…
Hello, there.
你們好
You guys, uh, doing all right?
你們，都還好嗎？
Yeah, we're fine.
我們還好
Because, look, when we get over to the other side,
如果你們需要的話，等我們過去了
we can just come back and grab your packs if you want?
可以再回來幫你們把包背過去
You know, it's easy for us.
這對我們來說沒什麼
- Not a problem. - Happy to help.
- 完全沒問題 - 很樂意幫忙
We like hard, we don't like easy. But thanks a lot, you know.
我們喜歡困難，不喜歡容易，但還是非常感謝
- All right, then. - Okay.
- 那好吧 - 好的
- Excuse us. All right. - Yep.
- 借過
- Nice guys.
- 小伙真不錯 - 是啊
- I hate 'em. - Me, too.
- 我恨他們 - 我也是
- That went well. - It was refreshing.
- 真順利 - 很提神
Bryson, you've got everything a man could want.
布萊森，你擁有一個男人想擁有的一切
And here you are, tramping around in the woods with me.
而你現在在這，和我一起在森林中穿梭
Seriously, what gives?
到底為什麼？
I don't know.
我也不知道
As John Muir once said, "Sometimes a man just has to"
就如約翰·繆爾曾說「有時，男人不得不找到麵包」
"get a loaf of bread and throw it into a sack, and jump over the back fence."
"扔進袋子裏，再跳進籬笆裏"
Oh, I got you.
我懂你
Life's a little too perfect inside that fence, huh?
籬笆裏面的生活太完美了，是吧？
- No, no, no... - Oh, you made sense, Bryson.
- 不，不，不… - 哦，你說的有道理，布萊森
You're a caged animal.
你是被關在籠子裏的野獸
You wanna get back into that forest. Live a little.
你想回到森林裏，好好活一把
- That's not it. - No, that's got to be it.
- 也不是這樣 - 不，肯定是這個
So why'd you come?
那你為什麼要來
I guess I didn't want to spend the rest of my life in jail.
我不想餘生在監獄裏度過
- What? - It's nothing, really.
- 什麼？ - 沒什麼，真的
Just a couple of outstanding warrants I didn't show up for and stuff like that.
只不過是幾個逮捕令我沒有配合執行而已
Jesus, Stephen, that's really not something you can run from.
天吶，史蒂芬，那可不是你逃得了的東西
Actually, you kind of can.
事實上，逃得了
Same old Stephen. Always running from something.
還是老樣子史蒂芬，一如既往地逃避
Oh, really? You're one to talk.
哦，真的嗎？你還有臉說我
Not you.
你還沒資格
Remind me again why we're out here?
提醒我一下咱們為什麼來這兒？
It's was not like you had something better to do.
你又不是有其他更好的事去忙
As I recall, in fact, you begged me to come.
我沒記錯的話，是你求我來的
I begged? I begged to come? I asked.
我求你？我求著來？我那是問你
You know what cracks me up, Bryson?
你知道你哪裏讓我覺得可笑嗎，布萊森？
Is how predictable your whole life has become, right down to the Volvo.
就是你整個人生一眼就能望到頭
God forbid somebody should evolve
好好奮鬥而不是虛度光陰的人
rather than squandering away their existence.
總是天理不容
I mean, look at you. All these years and you're still stuck at square one.
瞧瞧你，這麼多年了還是原地踏步
Hey, Bryson. Are you happy?
布萊森，你快樂嗎？
What the hell kind of a question is that?
這算個什麼破問題
Pretty important question, I'd say.
非常重要的問題
What, do you think you're happy?
那你覺得你快樂嗎？
I think...
我覺得…
The Smokies.
大霧山
Now this is interesting.
這下有意思了
Oh, God, this is amazing.
天吶，太美妙了
From here you can see all three kinds of rock.
在這能看到三種不同的岩石
There, you see that layered section across that slant?
你看到那邊斜坡上分層的部分了嗎？
- Yeah. - That's sedimentary.
- 看到了 - 那是沉積岩
And the dark stuff here, pushing up from underneath, that's igneous.
這邊黑不溜秋的玩意，就是從地下擠上來的這個 這是火成岩
Think volcanic.
想想火山
How do you know all this stuff?
你怎麼知道這些玩意的？
Well, there are these things called books.
有種東西就做書籍
- Oh. No kidding, they're called books? - Yeah, they're like TV for smart people.
- 你沒逗我吧，叫書籍？ - 沒錯，你就把它當做聰明人的電視
See, what we're talking about here, Katz, is time.
凱茲，咱們現在談論的是時間
Geologic time.
地質時間
Hundreds of thousands of years of enormous, shifting tectonic plates.
宏大的構造板塊千萬年以來不斷地移動
It's like the world being reborn from below while it's being eroded from above.
世界好像一邊在接受來自上層的侵蝕 一邊又從地下重生
Yeah. Well,
好吧
when we get back I'm gonna buy you a TV.
回去以後我要給你買台電視
Because nobody gives a fuck about shifting tectonic plates.
因為沒人會在乎這些移動的構造板塊
Well, I do.
我在乎啊
You know why?
知道為什麼嗎？
Because I'm curious, and I love being curious.
因為我很好奇，而且我樂此不疲
I like knowing things about the world that we're living in.
我喜歡瞭解我們所生活的世界
Well, I think it's all fucking rock.
我覺得這不過就是一堆破石頭
Oh, yeah?
是嗎？
I don't get bogged down in the minutiae.
我不會去追究事情的細枝末節
- I'm above the details. - You are?
- 我超脫在細節之上 - 是嗎？
I'm big picture, Bryson.
我注重大局，布萊森
Oh. How's that working out for you?
這對你幫助如何？
Ah, pretty, uh, fucking good.
啊，非常，啊，真他娘的大
Hello.
你好
We'd like a room, please.
我們需要一間房
Two rooms.
兩間
Oh, the Cubbies lost a double header, and they're 11 games back.
卡比隊連輸兩場，已經落後11場比賽了
Don't act surprised.
意料之中
Tonight would be preferable.
最好能讓我們今晚入住
Hello there?
你好
Where are the Red Sox?
紅襪隊呢？
Red Sox? Are you fucking kidding me? Whoa.
紅襪？你他媽的在逗我？
Excuse me, ma'am.
抱歉，女士
- Red Sox? - I live in New England.
- 紅襪隊？ - 我住在新英格蘭
Yeah, but Bryson, it's not about where you live, it's about who you are.
我知道，但是布萊森 問題你住哪，而在於你是哪種人
Oh, yeah? Well, I'm the kind of guy that likes it when a team wins now and then.
是嗎？我是那種喜歡 時不時能取得勝利的球隊的人
Well, you don't...
你不能…
You don't give up on a team just because they've had a few bad years.
你不能就因為一個球隊 有了幾年低谷期就放棄它
A few bad years? Jesus.
幾年低谷期？天吶
Baseball is about loyalty.
棒球關乎的是忠誠
Like, she knows what I'm talking about. Don't you?
她懂我在說什麼，不是嗎？
Would you two like a minute?
你們倆要獨處一會嗎？
Hi, I'm Jeannie. How can I help y'all?
你好，我叫簡寧，兩位需要什麼？
Mother, let go of the man's hand.
媽媽，放開人家的手
- Hi.
- 你好
Um, we'd like a couple of rooms. Please.
我們需要兩間房
Oh, sure. Where are you all from?
沒問題，你們從哪來的？
Uh, I live in New Hampshire, but I spent over 10 years in England.
我住在新罕布什爾 但我在英國待了十年
- Mostly in the north countryside... - He's from Iowa.
- 大多數時間都在北部的鄉村 - 他來自愛荷華
Well, the rooms are 40 a night and you can pay when you leave.
房費是40美元一晚，你們可以退房時結賬
Mother, I said, "Let go of the man's hand".
媽，我讓你放開人家的手啊
Thank you.
謝謝
Helluva grip.
握得真緊
The Cubs should sign her. She'd be the youngest in their bullpen.
卡比隊該簽了她 她會是隊裏最年輕的隊員
- I guess this is me. - Yeah, okay. I'm right here.
- 這間應該是我的 - 是的，我的在這
- Yeah. - Yeah. All right. I'll see you.
- 好吧 - 好，過會見
- Hi. - Hello, again.
- 你好
- How can I help you? - I just need some towels.
- 有什麼需要嗎？ - 我需要幾條毛巾
- Oh. I'm sorry about that. - That's fine.
- 真不好意思 - 沒關係
- Here, come with me. - Okay.
- 跟我來 - 好的
Yeah, it's family owned and operated. For three generations, if you can believe it.
你能相信嘛 這個旅館三代以來都是家庭私有並獨立經營
Oh, I can.
我信
It has a personal feel to it. That's pretty rare these days.
它有種家的感覺，這年頭非常罕見
Eighty-three years.
已經83年了
We, um... We added the restaurant 10 years ago.
我們…我們在十年前添了餐廳
- So you manage that, too? - Yeah.
- 餐廳也是你在管理嗎？ - 沒錯
Somebody's gotta do it.
總得有人管啊
It's not so bad. I get to meet interesting people.
這也挺好，我能遇到很多有意思的人
I'm not sure I qualify as interesting.
我不覺得我算得上是有意思的人
Oh, I wasn't talking about you.
哦，我沒在說你
Sorry. Could not resist.
抱歉，真的忍不住
- I'm glad I'm here to amuse you. - Yeah, yeah. Me, too.
- 很高興能逗你笑 - 是啊，我也很高興
This is you.
你到了
You must be exhausted.
你肯定累壞了
Holy shit.
見鬼
I... I gave you a couple extras.
我…我幫你多拿了幾條
Enjoy your shower.
洗個痛快澡
I will, thanks.
我會的，謝謝
Do you need anything else?
還有沒有別的需要？
No. Not at the moment.
沒，暫時沒有
Okay.
好吧
Well, you know where I am. All right.
你知道在哪找我
We're not here right now,
我們現在不在家
but please leave a message and thank you for calling. Bye.
請留言，感謝來電，再見
Hi, sweetie. It's me. Uh, just calling to say I love you.
喂，寶貝，是我 就是想對你說聲我愛你
Everything good on the home front?
家裏還好嗎？
She's impressed we haven't killed ourselves yet.
她挺驚訝咱們倆還活著
She's not the only one.
驚訝的人多了
Did you tell her about last night?
你有沒有和她提起昨晚？
What?
什麼？
You in a robe?
你穿著浴袍
The proprietress, I'm sure, was looking to hand over
我敢肯定，那個女店主想交給你的
more than just towels.
肯定不止是毛巾
You're out of your mind.
神經病
Am I?
是嗎？
Sure will make a steamy chapter in the book.
這件事寫出來能讓你的書更有看頭
Katz, I told you I'm not writing a book.
凱茲，告訴過你我不會寫書的
Listen, I'm going to go over to, uh, K-Mart.
聽著，我要去一趟折扣店
Get a couple of things. You okay?
買點東西，你一個人行嗎？
Oh, I'm in my happy place.
我在這好著呢
Good.
那就好
Idiot!
傻帽！
Oh, wait, wait.
稍等，稍等
Here, here.
來了，來了
- Here you are, ma'am. Here you go. - Oh, thank you.
- 您請進，女士，您請 - 哦，非常感謝
- Pardon me. - Hmm?
打擾一下
I'm so sorry. Do you think you could give me a hand here?
不好意思，能不能請你幫我個忙？
Well, certainly. I'd be happy to.
好的，沒問題，樂意效勞
What seems to be the problem?
有什麼問題嗎？
I'm having a difficult time removing my panties.
我的內褲卡住了
Well, luckily you're
你真幸運
- in the presence of an expert. - Oh.
我就是這方面的專家
May I?
我來？
- Oh, they're silk, aren't they? - Mmm-hmm.
哦，是絲綢的，對不對？
I'm a pantyologist.
我可是內褲學家
Really? I've never heard of that.
是嗎？從沒聽過這個詞
these aren't gonna do you much good.
這樣穿著可能不太好
Well, they might not do me much bad, either.
也沒什麼不好
No.
沒錯
- Jesus, Bryson. - Don't ask.
- 天吶，布萊森 - 不要問
You been screwing hogs again?
你又去吃獨食了？
You're just jealous.
你就嫉妒吧
Actually, I'm not.
我才沒有
In your absence, my romantic life has taken a turn for the better.
你不在的時候，我的浪漫史迎來了轉折點
Remember the laundromat?
記得自助洗衣店嗎？
Her name is Beulah.
她的名字叫比拉
Seriously?
真的假的？
Yeah, seriously. And she's got a beautiful body.
是真的，她有著美妙的軀體
Buried under two hundred pounds of fat.
被埋在兩百磅的脂肪之下
But then, you know I kinda like a little meat on the bone.
但話說回來，我也挺喜歡帶點肉感的
Sure, as long as you don't have to remove a wall to get her out of the house.
好吧，只要不用拆了牆 才能把她從家裏接走就好了
How did this happen?
你們怎麼搞上的？
She asked me if I would come take a look at her panties.
她問我能不能看一眼她的內褲
- What? - They were caught in the agitator.
- 什麼？ - 內褲夾在轉筒上了
And they were shredded.
而且被絞碎了
So I'm gonna meet her this afternoon in front of the fire station.
我今天下午要去消防站見她
Is that where she keeps her spare underwear?
她的備用內褲都放在那嗎？
I'm telling you, man, I felt a stiffening of the old resolve.
跟你講，夥計，我覺得我的老槍硬了一下
- Oh, yeah? - I got her these.
- 是嗎？ - 我給她買了這個
Oh, she's a big woman.
她可大著呢
Where'd you get these?
你從哪買的？
K-Mart. I took a cab.
折扣店，我打車去的
Um, I thought I'd give 'em to her at dinner.
我想在晚飯的時候送給她
As an ice-breaker.
來打破僵局
You're gonna give those to her in a restaurant?
你要在餐廳裏給她這玩意？
Yeah.
對啊
Unless you think it's a bad idea.
除非你覺得這個主意很糟
No. I think that's a great idea.
不，我覺得這個想法很棒
Good.
那就好
- You had the turkey, right? - Yes.
- 您點了火雞，對嗎 - 沒錯
- Enjoy. - All right.
- 請慢用 - 好的
We go. We go.
咱們快走，咱們快走
- What are you talking about? - There's some guy looking for me!
- 你在說什麼？ - 有人在找我！
Some guy?
什麼人？
Beulah's husband.
比拉的老公
- Beulah's got a husband? - Yeah.
- 比拉有老公？ - 是啊
I mean, there's only two guys on the planet that would go to bed with her,
全世界就只有兩個男人願意和她上床
and here we are in the same damned town!
他娘的還在同一個鎮上
So what happened?
發生了什麼？
I'm standing in front of the fire station like we planned.
我就如計劃的一樣站在消防站門口
And then around the corner comes this red pickup and it screeches to a halt.
不久之後來了一輛紅色卡車猛然停下
And this big guy, he's angry, he gets out,
出來了個氣壞了的大胖子
and he's walking up towards me, and he's going like this.
他朝我走來，一邊說
"I want to talk to you."
「我要和你談談」
- So what did you do? - I ran.
- 那你怎麼辦？ - 我逃了
You ran?
你逃了？
Yeah. I can move like a jack-rabbit if I have to.
如果必要的話我能跑得比兔子還快
- So he didn't catch you? - No, no. He's 600 pounds.
- 那他沒抓住你？ - 沒，沒有，他600磅呢
He's not exactly a track star.
又不是什麼運動健將
He's cruising around now in his red pickup truck looking for me.
他現在開著他的紅色卡車來回找我
I been running through back yards, clothes lines, all sorts of shit.
我穿過各家後院，晾衣架 各種亂七八糟的東西
- Well, you're safe now. - This guy is...
- 你現在安全了 - 那傢伙…
Red pickup!
紅卡車
And there's another one!
又一輛！
Come on, Bryson, we need a plan!
拜託，布萊森，我們需要一個計劃！
Why don't you go out and talk to the guy, huh? I'm sure he's reasonable.
要不你去和那傢伙談談？他肯定很通情達理
That's your plan?
這就是你的計劃？
I don't need a plan. I'm not being chased.
我不需要計劃，他們又沒追我
Now, come on, Bryson, we gotta get outta here.
求你了，布萊森，我們必須離開這
- Yeah. - Come on, don't mess around with me.
- 是啊 - 拜託，別逗我玩了
Please?
求你了
- Come on! - Yeah, yeah.
- 快點！ - 好了，好了
Hey buddy, you in there?
那傢伙，你在裏面嗎？
It's Bubba T. Flubba! Are you in there, boy? Come out, you chicken shit!
我是巴巴緹·付羅巴！你在裏面吧？ 快出來，你個膽小鬼！
Come on! Don't mess around!
拜託！別逗我了！
Open up!
快開門
I know you're in there, you son of a bitch!
我知道你在裏面，你個狗娘養的
Holy shit.
我操
He's here!
他來了！
I don't care where the hell you are,
不論你在哪
I'll knock every one of these damned doors down!
我要把這裏每扇門都敲一遍！
Come on, I know you're in here somewhere, you son of a bitch!
快點，我知道你就在這，你個王八蛋！
I don't care where you are, I'm gonna find you!
不論你在哪，我都會找到你！
I want to know who's been messing with my Beulah!
我要知道是誰在調戲我家比拉！
- Bring your ass out here! - Come on, Bryson!
- 給我滾過來！ - 快點，布萊森！
Pull me through! He's at the door!
把我拉過去！他就在門口！
Open the goddamned door!
他媽的給老子開門！
Come on, move it! Move it!
快點，快走！快走！
But what about Basel? When we stole the boat?
巴塞爾怎麼辦？我們偷了她的船
We didn't steal the boat, we borrowed the boat.
咱們沒偷船，咱們是借船
Yes, well, the girl's uncle with the shotgun, he saw it differently.
好吧，那女孩的叔叔可不這麼看，他還有槍
He sure did.
他確實不這麼認為
You know, you missed out in Greece.
知道嗎，你在希臘錯過了很多
I'd kind of had my fill by that point.
我那時候已經沒什麼好錯過的了
When you said you were gonna go to England, I thought you'd last,
當你說你準備去英國的時候 我覺得你能堅持
one week. Tops.
頂多一周
- Well, I met a gal. - Yeah.
我遇到了一個女孩
And that was that.
就是這樣
Well... Yeah, thank you.
哦，謝謝
Cathy seems great. But obviously you've been with other women.
凱西很好，但你肯定還有過其他女人
Never?
從來沒有？
In the last 40 years?
在過去40年都沒有？
Nope.
沒有
Bullshit, you son of a bitch.
放屁，你個混球
I saw you undress that proprietress six ways to Sunday.
我看你扒光人家女店主的花樣可多著呢
- You can't tell me you didn't. - Well...
- 你可別說你沒有 - 好吧…
One woman all these years?
這些年就這一個女人？
Yep.
沒錯
That can't be good for you.
這可不太好
I mean, when was the last time that you even got a, uh...
你最近一次是什麼時候…
Well, never mind. I know how married women are.
算了，我知道女人婚後是什麼樣
Really? Is that so?
是嗎？
Yeah. Trust me. I've been with way more married women than you have.
是啊，相信我，我上過的有夫之婦比你多多了
Hey, Katz, you awake?
凱茲，你醒著嗎？
No.
沒有
What was that?
那是什麼？
How the hell should I know?
我他媽怎麼知道？
It sounded big.
聽上去挺大的
Everything sounds big in the woods, Bryson.
森林裏什麼聽上去都大，布萊森
It's probably just a skunk. Go to bed.
或許就是只臭鼬，睡你的吧
Did you pack a knife?
你帶沒帶刀？
No.
沒有
Nothing sharp?
沒有鋒利的東西嗎？
Nail clippers.
指甲刀
Swell.
好極了
Just leave it alone, Bryson. It will go away.
別管它了布萊森，它自己會離開的
what are you going to do? Give it a pedicure?
你該怎麼辦？給它修個腳？
Jesus! Two fucking bears staring right at me.
天啊！他娘的兩頭熊就這麼盯著我
Oh, god dammit, Bryson, get some sleep.
我操你娘，布萊森，快點睡覺
Holy shit.
我操
If they come for us, play dead.
如果它們來了，裝死
If they come for us, we are dead.
如果它們來了，咱們就死定了
No, wait, wait, wait.
別，等等，等等，等等
That's grizzlies. Wait a minute.
這是灰熊，等一下
Motherfuck. They're tearing everything apart.
操他娘，它們把咱們的東西都撕碎了
Okay. "Stand up as tall as you can to intimidate the bear."
"站得越高越好，去嚇住熊"
Intimidate the bear? They're fucking bears!
嚇熊？他娘的那可是熊！
We've got to scare them off.
咱們必須嚇跑它們
Get! Scat!
隨機應變！
You gotta put this in the book.
你一定得把這寫進書裏
- There's not going to be a goddamned book. - Oh.
- 我不會寫書的 - 哦
Jeez. Damn.
操
Come on, we're having fun.
拜託，出來玩開心一點啦
Holy shit.
我操
- Look at this. - What?
- 看這個 - 什麼？
This is the trail.
這是山道地圖
Here we are. We're not even halfway there.
咱們在這，連一半都沒走完
- This can't be right. - Son of a bitch.
- 不可能 - 狗娘養的
No way that's to scale.
這地圖比例不對
It says, "Map to Scale".
這寫著「與地圖成比例」
That's it. New plan.
這樣吧，新計劃
God damn it.
操他娘
I'm telling you, Bryson, there's a lot of advantages.
我跟你講，布萊森，這有很多好處
You want to drive the Appalachian Trail?
你想開車穿越阿帕拉契山道？
No, no, just jump ahead. Pick up the trail a little further north.
不，不，只不過是跳躍一下 選一條北邊一點的山路
You know, we can rent a car over here.
你知道，咱們可以在這租輛車
Then we're mobile, we'll see more.
那樣的話咱們機動性就高了，也能看到更多
Check out local points of interest.
去看看當地特色景點
Bigger field of vision.
視野也更開闊
Bryson, as a friend,
布萊森，作為朋友
do this for me.
就當幫我這個忙吧
Hey, you're not gonna believe the deal I got on this.
嘿，你肯定猜不到我花了多少錢租這車
Katz...
凱茲…
This beauty represents not one, but two upgrades.
這個美人提升的地方可不是一處，而是兩處
Satellite radio, leather seats, sunroof. Same price as a Camry.
衛星廣播，皮革座椅，防曬 和凱美瑞一樣的價格
If you can believe that.
你敢相信嗎
Here you go, Mr. Katz. Just three quick initials and you'll be on your way.
凱茲先生，再很快簽三個名您就可以上路了
We can't do this.
咱們不能這樣
Of course we can.
咱們當然可以
I came out here to accomplish something.
我出來是為了完成某件事情
Not to just give up when things got a little tough.
而不是在困難的時候半途而廢
We're not giving up, Bryson.
咱們沒有放棄啊，布萊森
What does it matter if we skip the shitty parts?
跳過艱難的部分又怎麼了？
- No one's gonna know. - Well, I will.
- 沒人會知道 - 我會知道
I'm not a quitter. I know it served you well in your life,
我可不會退縮 我知道退縮對你的人生來說很管用
- but I finish what I start. - Bryson.
- 但我要有始有終 - 布萊森
- Did we not both see the same map? - Yeah.
- 咱們看到的難道不是同一張地圖嗎？ - 是啊
You have no chance of finishing this trail.
你壓根不可能走完整個山路
None. Zero. Zilch.
絕不，從不，永不
Well, I'm sure as hell gonna try.
我能確信我會盡我所能
Hike until you die.
走到死嗎
Where do I sign up?
我該從何說起？
We're two old men, Bryson. You gotta quit thinking otherwise.
咱們都是糟老頭了，布萊森 別以為自己不是
Speak for yourself.
說你自己呢吧
Just because you don't accept something, Bryson, doesn't mean it's not true.
事情不會因為你不接受而不存在
- Well, that's interesting, coming from you. - Just three initials is all...
- 聽你說這些可真有意思 - 只要三個簽名就夠了…
It's everything with you, Bryson.
都是你自己的事，布萊森
Christ, if someone asks you where you're from, you can't even answer.
天啊，你連人家問你從哪來這種問題都回答不了
Oh, so I'm the one in denial, huh?
哦，我倒成了逃避事實的人了？
When you're the one hiding whiskey in your pack.
而你卻在包裏藏著威士忌
- Oh. - I saw the bottle.
我看到瓶子了
So I guess neither of us can accept who we really are.
所以我想咱倆都無法接受自己
Oh, I know who I am and why I'm here.
我知道我是什麼樣的人，為什麼來這
I came out here to be with you,
我來這是為了陪你
to sneak in one last adventure before it's too late.
趁還來得及，來一場最後的冒險
Well, this is my adventure, and you signed on.
這是我的冒險，你是自願參與的
You can do whatever you want, but you're not going to drag me down.
你愛幹嘛幹嘛，但別把我拖下水
- If you could just use that pen to sign... - Fine!
- 你能不能用那根筆簽一下… - 好吧！
- I don't want your car. - Excuse me?
- 我不想租車了 - 你說什麼？
I don't want your goddamn car.
我不想要你那輛破車了
Fine!
好啊！
- Well, that's the spirit. - Yeah. Fuck.
- 就要這種精神 - 好吧，操他娘的
I sure am glad we aren't driving right now.
真高興現在咱們不在車裏
- You? - I couldn't be happier.
- 你呢？ - 再高興不過
You know, 50 years ago,
50年前
one in every four of these trees was an American Chestnut.
這些樹的四分之一都是美洲栗樹
- You know what that is? You ever seen one? - I think so.
- 你知道栗樹是什麼嗎？有沒有見過？ - 應該見過
It's incredible.
這很不可思議
They rise from the forest floor, clear to the top. 100 feet.
它們從森林地面長起，高達100英尺
And their branches contain an acre of leaves. An acre.
它們能長出一公頃的葉子，一公頃啊
You look into these woods
你看到這片森林
and you think they've always been there and always will be,
想著它們一直都在這並將永遠如此
like this old oak tree here.
就像這棵老橡樹
And then you think about the poor unsuspecting American Chestnut,
再想想那些可憐的毫無準備的美洲栗樹
and think just in a lifetime... Poof. Gone. Just like that.
想著短短一生的時間…彭一下就沒了
What happened to it?
美洲栗樹怎麼了？
A fungus.
真菌
You know. Just, you know, time. Nature.
就是，時間，大自然
You know, Bryson, I wasn't actually hiding this.
知道嗎，布萊森，我並沒想藏著它
I wasn't lying about being dry either.
戒酒的事情我也沒騙你
The thing is, Bryson, I love to drink. Everything about it.
關鍵是，布萊森，我喜歡喝酒 喜歡關於酒的一切
I love the taste.
我愛它的味道
And that buzz you get after you've had a couple.
以及喝下兩口後的嗡嗡聲
I love the smell of the tavern, right down to the urinal cakes.
我愛酒館的味道，甚至是酒館的便池
But instead of going into the taverns like everybody else,
但和像其他人一樣去酒館相比
I go home to my little apartment, and heat my TV dinner,
我選擇回到自己的小公寓，熱一下快餐
and feel all virtuous like I'm supposed to.
並感受所有我喜歡的美好事物
But you know, night after night it's hard to persuade yourself
但你知道，日復一日 你很難去說服自己相信
that you're living a rich and thrilling existence.
自己的生活是富有的，有激情的
I mean, if they had a fun-o-meter
我是說，要是有快樂測量器的話
the needle wouldn't exactly be jumping into the orgasmic zone.
指針可能不會跳到有激情的那個區域
You know what I'm saying?
你懂我在說什麼吧？
I mean, there's just this hole in my life where drinking used to be.
我的人生就有這麼一塊空缺 曾經靠酒精來填補
I know I can't drink.
我知道我不能再喝了
I mean, one drink will lead to 10.
喝了第一杯就會有第十杯
And the next thing, I'll find myself underneath a bridge somewhere.
等我反應過來的時候已經在某個橋下面了
That's why I carry this.
這就是我帶上它的原因
To remind myself that I can.
來提醒我自己我能辦到
Or maybe I carry it in case I can't.
或者可能是為我忍不住做好準備
Here.
給你
Open it.
把它打開
It's sealed.
是密封的
Give it to me.
拿給我
It's shaking.
在抖呢
Do you think I have it in me
你覺得我能不能做到
to never have another drink for the rest of my life?
餘生中滴酒不沾
Yeah. I do.
我覺得你能
That was a nice moment.
這一刻很美妙
Real dramatic.
像電影一樣
Christ if I don't already regret it.
老天，如果我不是已經後悔了的話
Ain't that life.
這不就是人生嗎
Watch it.
小心
You know, Bryson, I still dream about Amorina. You remember her?
你知道嗎，布萊森 我有時還會夢到阿莫琳娜，你還記得她媽？
Oh, God, can't forget a girl like that.
哦，天啊，那種女孩一輩子都忘不掉
You know guys like us aren't supposed to meet women named Amorina.
咱們這種男人就不該遇到叫阿莫琳娜的女人
Disturbs the natural order.
會擾亂自然順序的
Still the best boobs I've ever seen, and I've seen a lot of boobs, Bryson.
依舊是我見過的最完美的胸 我見過的胸可多了，布萊森
Yeah, I'll bet.
恩，我信
Hey, you remember her sister?
你還記得她姐姐嗎？
Oh, God, that poor girl. They couldn't have been sisters.
天啊，那個可憐的女孩 她倆怎麼可能是姐妹
If you're going to be ugly, you better be funny.
你要是長得醜那就最好幽默點
And if you're ugly and you're not funny, you better have money.
你要是長得醜又不幽默，那你最好有錢
And if you're zero for three, you better be slutty.
要是你三樣都沒有，那你最好騷一點
- She was. - Wait a minute, how did you know that, huh?
- 她確實很騷 - 等一下，你怎麼知道的？
Well, actually...
實際上…
Jesus Christ.
我的天
Next time you do that, let me know, okay?
下次你再這樣，提前告訴我一下，好嗎？
It's more fun if it's a surprise.
你不知道才好玩
- You all right? - You okay?
你還好嗎？你沒事吧？
Yeah.
沒事
Jesus.
天吶
We are fucked.
咱們完蛋了
Monumentally.
徹底完了
There's no way out over here.
沒有出去的路
- What are you doing? - I'm gonna get us out of here.
- 你在幹嘛？ - 我要把咱們帶出去
- Give me your pants. - Uh, no, no.
- 把你褲子給我 - 啊，不，不
You've been planning this the whole time, Bryson.
你一直都在謀劃這件事，布萊森
Just give me your pants, okay?
把褲子給我就行了，好嗎？
Okay.
好吧
Okay. Knot this thing.
好了，把它繫起來
- All right? - Okay.
- 成了 - 好吧
Here we go.
來吧
It is embarrassing, Bryson. Give me that thing.
真丟人，布萊森，把這玩意給我
You gotta admit, pretty good aim, though, huh?
你得承認我瞄得很準，對吧？
Yeah. But you're supposed to hold on to one end of it.
是的，但你本該抓住一頭的
Well, you know, it's not that high.
這也不算太高
Here, I got it. You see this? You could come up here.
我來搞定，看到這個了嗎？你先站到這兒
I'll be around like this and you could climb up on my shoulders.
我就這樣站在旁邊，然後你爬到我肩膀上
- Wanna try it? - Okay.
- 要試試嗎？ - 好吧
Okay. Hang on.
好的，等一下
- Okay? - Yeah.
- 好了嗎？ - 好了
We can make it. Hold...
咱們能行的，抓穩
- You all right? What? - Yeah, hang on. You know...
- 你沒事吧？ - 沒事，等一下…
This isn't... You've got to get lower, so I can get on your shoulders.
這不行…你得更低一點我才能爬上你肩膀
Fuck. Fine.
操，好吧
Okay.
好了
- Okay? - Yeah.
- 行了嗎？ - 行了
Okay. There we go.
好的，這就對了
Bryson, I really don't like this.
布萊森，我真的很討厭這樣
No, no, it's good, it's good. Now, you stand up. Stand up.
別，別，這樣挺好，挺好的 現在，你站起來，站起來
Jesus!
天吶！
Who are we kidding?
咱們在騙誰啊？
For Christ's sake, I can't even get myself up from that position.
老天哪，我都沒法自己爬起來
- All right, then. I'll stand on your back. - How about I stand on your back?
- 那行，那我就站你背上 - 要不我站你背上怎麼樣？
You know,
知道嗎
I think we're really stuck here.
咱們真的被困在這了
Yeah. Yeah, we are.
是啊，是啊，咱們困在這了
You know, on the East coast hardwoods are dying.
知道嗎，東海岸的闊葉樹正在瀕臨滅絕
Not just the chestnut,
不光光是栗樹
but the elm's on its way, too, you know.
榆樹也要步後塵了
Fifty years, this could all be gone.
再有五十年，就都沒了
Thirty days.
三十天
Thirty days in jail. I was afraid of 30 days.
在看守所待了三十天，擔驚受怕了三十天
Compared to this,
但跟現在比
I mean, it's like a goddamned trip to the spa.
那次蹲監獄簡直就像做水療
God, all I've done is write forewords for books
在過去的四年半里我除了給書寫寫序言
for the last four and a half years.
一事無成
I should have just retired.
我真該退休了
Catherine was right, what the hell am I trying to prove?
凱瑟琳說得對 我到底有什麼好證明的？
Women love a felony record.
女人們就愛有犯罪記錄的
Maybe not up in New Hampshire, where you are.
或許在你們新罕布什爾行不通
But in Des Moines, it would have served me well.
但是在得梅因，肯定會讓我很吃香
Do you just get to the point where
你是要直接到那個
it's all about ailments, and medications, and funerals,
全是疾病，吃藥和葬禮
and who's being diagnosed with what,
以及誰又被診斷出了什麼病
and everyone's just waiting around for the end.
最後所有人都在等死的終點嗎？
- Holy shit. - What?
- 我操他娘 - 怎麼了？
I just realized, we're the guy in the article.
我剛反應過來咱們就是那篇文章裏的人
You know, the, uh, decomposed guy. Remember that?
想起來沒？就那個腐爛的屍體
That'll be us.
那就是咱倆的下場
How long does it take a body to decompose?
屍體腐爛要多久？
Well, you don't have to worry.
這你倒是不用擔心
You're so chock-full of preservatives, you'll be on this ledge forever.
你身體裏塞的都是防腐劑，你會永垂不朽的
Well, scientists will come from all over the world to study me, you know.
全世界的科學家都會跑來研究我
I miss Catherine.
我想凱瑟琳了
I miss Des Moines.
我想得梅因了
You know, I haven't missed a State Fair in 39 years.
知道嗎，我39年來一次國家博覽會都沒錯過
I always say, "When I miss one",
我總是說，「我錯過的話只有一種可能」
"I'll be dead."
「那就是我死了」
You know, she makes this little sound whenever I hug her.
每當我抱她的時候她都會發出一種聲音
I don't even think she knows it.
估計她自己都沒意識到
I've never told her how much I love that.
我從未和她說我多愛她那個樣子
I just don't want her to think this trip had anything to do with her.
我只是不想讓她覺得我這次出來是因為她
She knows.
她知道的
Believe me, women have a way of knowing these things.
相信我，女人總是會知道這種事情
Yeah, but still, I'd like to tell her.
沒錯，但我還是想親口告訴她
Well, write her a note.
給她寫紙條吧
People love to get notes.
人們都喜歡收紙條
- Hey, you know, you're right. - Yeah.
- 你說的對 - 是啊
Hey, that's a great idea.
這主意很好
You know, Bryson, you're the only guy I'd risk my life with.
知道嗎，布萊森 你是唯一值得我冒生命危險的人
I want you to know that.
我得讓你知道
And the only asshole who can get me out on a ledge in the middle of nowhere.
你也是唯一一個 能把我帶到這鳥不拉屎的地方的混蛋
I'm sorry we lost touch.
很遺憾咱們多年沒有聯繫
I know. Yeah, me too.
我懂，我也是
Goddamned gorgeous night.
這夜空真他娘的美
It sure is.
確實如此
You think there's anyone else on Earth
你說會不會有其他人仰望夜空
looking up at the sky and seeing as many stars as we are?
也看到了現在這麼多星星？
I don't know.
我不知道
I gotta be looking at a million.
我看到的肯定有一百萬個
The naked eye can see 2,000.
裸眼只能看到2000個
Well, then I really got great eyes 'cause I'm looking at a million.
那我的視力肯定很牛，因為我看到了一百萬個
Alpha Centauri's the closest. That's four and a half light years away.
最近的是半人馬星座，距離是4.5光年
Four and a half? That's not bad.
4.5？那還不賴
Each light year is six trillion miles, so that's...
一光年是六兆英里，所以一共有…
twenty six trillion miles.
二十六兆英里
- Twenty-six trillion. That's the closest? - Yep.
- 二十六兆，那還是最近的？ - 沒錯
And there's one hundred billion stars in our galaxy.
我們的銀河系有一千億顆星
There's more galaxies in the universe than there are grains of sand on earth.
而宇宙中的星系數量比地球上的沙粒還多
That is big.
那可真夠大的
- And we are small. - Yeah.
- 而我們很渺小 - 是啊
What the...
搞什麼…
People?
有人？
People? People?
有人？有人？
- People?
- 有人？
People! Hello!
有人嗎！喂！
- Hello! Hello, down here! - Hello!
- 喂！喂！在下面！ - 喂！
Help, please!
救命！
Help!
救命啊！
Hey, down there.
嘿，下面的
You've got to be shitting me.
你他娘的在逗我
What happened to your pants?
你褲子怎麼了？
- Uh, it's a long story. - Copy that.
- 說來話長 - 明白了
You guys just stay put. We'll get you out of there.
你們在那別動，我們這就拉你們上來
- Nice fellas. - Yeah.
- 小伙真不錯 - 是啊
- I love those guys. - Me, too.
- 我愛死他們了 - 我也是
- You still got some of that jerky? - Yeah.
- 你還有牛肉幹嗎？ - 是的
You still good on water?
你的水還夠嗎？
- About three-quarters. You? - Yeah, same.
- 還剩四分之三，你呢？ - 我也是
- Hey, Stephen? - Yeah?
- 史蒂芬？ - 怎麼了？
Do you want to go home?
你想回家嗎？
Yeah, I do. I really do.
想，我想，我真的想
We weren't even close, were we?
咱們還差得遠呢，不是嗎？
What are you talking about? We did it, Bryson.
胡說什麼呢？咱們做到了，布萊森
We never even laid eyes on Mount Katahdin.
咱們連卡塔丁山的影都沒見到
Another mountain? How many mountains do you need to see?
又是山？你還要再看多少山才夠？
- That's one way of looking at it. - That's the only way of looking at it.
- 你這麼說倒也對 - 我說的本來就很對
As far as I'm concerned, we walked the Appalachian Trail.
反正對我來說，咱們走過了阿帕拉契山道
We walked it in the heat, we walked it in the snow,
咱們風裏來雨裏去
we walked it until our feet bled.
走路走到腳都破了
We hiked the Appalachian Trail, Bryson.
我們徒步走過了阿帕拉契山道，布萊森
Maybe you're right.
或許你是對的
- You guys called a cab? All right. - Yeah.
- 是你們叫的出租車，對吧？ - 是的
This thing's heavy. You been carrying it awhile?
這東西可真重，你們一直都背著？
All the way from Georgia.
從佐治亞一路背來
You don't say. Good for you, fellas. Hey, where you guys from?
真的嗎？真厲害，朋友 你們是哪裏人？
Iowa.
愛荷華
That's not possible.
不可能
No such thing as a Red Sox fan from Iowa.
愛荷華怎麼會有紅襪隊的球迷呢
Here you go.
給你
"Dearest Catherine..." That's as far as you got?
「親愛的凱瑟琳…」你就這點能耐？
It's lucky we were saved.
咱們活著回來太幸運了
There are certain things you just can't put into words.
有些事情是不能用文字來表達的
Safe journey, okay?
一路小心，好嗎？
Yeah.
好的
You still owe me 600 bucks.
你還欠我600美元呢
You know I'm good for it, right?
你知道我壓根沒放在心上，對吧？
Oh, yeah.
我知道
Remember me?
還記得我嗎？
She had one hell of a stack of pancakes. Katz.
她吃了一大堆的煎餅 ——凱茲
I hate your guts.
我恨死你了
Never buy underpants for a woman you don't know.
永遠別從不認識的女人那裏買內褲
Fuckers still didn't get me.
狗日的還沒找到我
Bryson, just wondering, what's next?
布萊森，就是想問問接下來幹嘛？